Finding Aid for the Nat Segaloff Papers PASC.0354
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Research Material, 1970-; Series 3.
  - O'Brien, Ted: Interview, 1981 October 1; audio cassette (Box 26)
    Interview with the anchorman (Boston).
  - O'Connor, Rory: Interview, 1979 May 5; audio cassette (Box 26)
    Interview with the reporter, producer.
  - Orson Welles Film School Seminars, 8 audio cassettes (Box 26)
    The Project -- Money -- Production -- Distribution -- Porno.
    Segaloff taught at this school in Cambridge MA. Tapes 178-185
  - Periodicals, 1943 December 15-1952 July 7,1996 September (Box 83)
    The Hollywood Reporter (vols. LXXVI no. 17; CXVI, no. 33; SCVI, no. 34; XCC, no. 1); Variety, Sept. 9-15, 1996 (1 vol.)
    All contain information on the Hollywood Blacklist.
  - Perry, Eleanor: Interview, 1979 April 24; audio cassette (Box 26)
    Interview with the screenwriter of "David and Lisa" and "Last Summer."
    Tape 176
  - Petersen, William L.: Interview, 1988 April 24; audio cassette (Box 25)
    Interview with the actor about William Friedkin.
    Interview conducted in Chicago, IL. Tape 270.
  - Petersen, William: Interview, 1988 July 22; mini cassettes (Box 82)
  - Platner, Robert: Interview, audio cassette (Box 26)
    Platner is a well-regarded Boston chef.
  - Pogash, Jeffrey: Interview, 1980 November 17; audio cassette (Box 26)
    Interview conducted at Boston University.
    Tape 168
  - Present Memory Interview, 1989 October 9; audio cassette (Box 25)
    Interview with Richard Broadman and Susan Steiner, creators of the independent film, Present Memory.
  - Quinlan, Sterling "Red": Interview, 1988 April 26; audio cassette (Box 25)
    Interview with the author and broadcasting executive about William Friedkin. Quinlan also wrote the book "The Million Dollar Lunch," about WHDH-TV losing its license.
    Interview conducted in Chicago, IL. Tape 274
  - Rampage Seminar, 1987 November 19; audio cassette (Box 25)
    Seminar given at USC by William Friedkin.
    Tape no. 279
  - Redstone, Summer, 1989 February 24; mini cassettes (Box 82)
  - Rescue, (The) Interviews, 2 audio cassettes (Box 25)
    Interviews about the film, "The Rescue" with: actors, Michael Gates Phenecie, Marc Price, Edward Albert, Kevin Dillon, Charles Haid, and Ned Vaughn; writer, Jim Thomas; producer, Laura Ziskin, and director, Ferdinand Fairfax.
    Tape nos. 263, 264.
  - Resurrection Seminar, 2 audio cassettes (Box 26)
    Seminar on the film, recorded on Mackinac Island, MI.
    Tapes 191, 192
  - Richert, Bill: Interview, 1979 September 25; audio cassette (Box 26)
    Interview with the writer/director of "Winter Kills."
  - Roach, Janet: Interview, 1987 August 5; audio cassette (Box 25)
    The screenwriter talks about the film, "Mr. North."
    Tape 244.
  - Robinson, Joel: Interview, audio cassette (Box 26)
    Interview with the inventor.
  - Rogers, Wayne: Interview, 1979 May 16; audio cassette (Box 26)
    Interview with the actor, realtor.
  - Rosenblum, Ralph: Interview, 1988 February 16; audio cassette (Box 25)
    Interview with the editor of the films, "A Thousand Clowns" and "The Producers."
    Interview conducted in New York City. Tape 277
  - Rush, Richard: Interview (Box 82)
    Interview with the director of "Stunt Man."
  - Russell, Kurt: Interview, audio cassette (Box 26)
    Interview with the actor.
    Tape 171
  - Russo, Vito: Interview, 1988 September 7; audio cassette (Box 25)
    Interview with the historian/gay activist.
    Tape 253.
  - Sahlins, Bernie: Interview, 1988 February 24; audio cassette (Box 25)
    Interview with the writer, director, comedian and co-founder of the Second City improvisational troup.
    Telephone interview. Tape 278
  - Sanger, Jonathan: Interview, 1988 February 22; audio cassette (Box 25)
    Interview with the producer/director.
    Interview conducted in Los Angeles. Tape no. 272
  - Saroyan, Lucy: Interview, audio cassette (Box 26)
  - Schlessinger, John: Interview, 1988 October 8; audio cassette (Box 25)
    Interview with the director, Schlessinger, and actress, Shanda Ozmi, of the film "The Believers."
  - Shagan, Steve: Interview, 1980 December 1; audio cassette (Box 26)
    Interview with the writer of, "Save the Tiger" and "The Formula."
  - Shaw, Tom: Interview, 1987 August 7; audio cassette (Box 25)
    Production manager for John Huston. Includes information about the film, "Mr. North."
    Tape nos. 242, 244
  - Silliphant, Stirling, 1996 April 22; mini cassette; papers; reading glasses (Box 59)
    Silliphant's personal telephone book; rights document regarding Segaloff interview; reading glasses/photograph; minicassette recording of wife talking about Silliphant's death. See Segaloff's full-length Silliphant biography, "The Fingers of the God."
    See also: Series I Projects, for Segaloff monograph notes.
  - Stan Freberg "Who Listens to Radio" Demo, 7 " open reel audio tape (Box 5)
    Classic radio campaign for Bekins Van Lines.
  - Stanton, Harry Dean: Interview, 1987 August 15; audio cassette (Box 25)
    The actor talks about his role in the film, "Mr. North" with actress, Mary Stuart Masterson.
    Tape no. 243.
  - Starger, Martin: Interview, 1980 July 28; audio cassette (Box 26)
    Interview with Lew Grade's producer, about "Raise the Titanic."
  - Stelloff, Skip: Interview, 1987 September 6; audio cassette (Box 25)
    Producer of the film, "Mr. North."
    tape no. 241.
  - Syatt, Dick: Interview, audio cassette (Box 26)
    Interview with the radio personality.
  - Sylbert, Anthea: Interview, audio cassette (Box 26)
  - Sylbert, Anthea: Interview, 2 audio cassettes (Box 26)
    Tapes 195, 194
  - Tape 169, 1980; audio cassette (Box 82)
    John & Celia Milius -- Neil Simon -- Jay Sandrich, party at Frank Price's house.
  - Tape 208, 1980 June; audio cassette (Box 82)
    Mark Rydell -- David Forbes -- Claudia Weil -- Garrison True -- Frank Price -- John Milius.
  - Tape 259, 1989 January 26-February 23; audio cassette (Box 82)
    John Rochester -- John Milius.
  - Tape Interviews nos. 104-137, audio cassettes (Box 29)
    Michael Bright -- Patrick Macnee -- Joe Camp -- Brian Renfro -- Wolfgang Reitherman -- Tim Conway -- Phil Kaufman -- Lorraine and Ed Warren -- Jim Rich -- Monica Collins -- Carolyn McCurry - Next Move Company -- Marjie Short -- Doug Herrick -- David Foster -- Martha Pinson -- Attack of the Sequel Monsters -- Andrew Silver -- Donna McKechnie -- James Bridges -- Waiters' Round Table -- James Brolin -- Harvard Square Street People -- Joseph E. Levine -- Kenneth Geist -- Cheech & Chong -- Jacob Brackman -- Louise Fletcher -- Ben Orr -- Robert Carradine -- Richard Chew -- Northeast Solar Energy Center -- Cloris Leachman -- Jon Lipsky -- Michael Fremer -- Hal Needham -- Candy Clark -- Gerald Lewis -- Mandel & Lydon -- Toronto Air Show Briefing -- Bertrand Blier -- Jan Egelson -- Henry Thomaszewski -- Sylvia Kristel -- Peter Yates -- Daniel Stern -- Dennis Quaid -- Martin Short -- Joe Dante -- Mike Finnell -- Peter Coyote -- Leslie Dixon -- Shelly Long -- Bette Midler -- Arthur Hiller -- George Carlin -- Emilio Estevez -- John Badham -- Richard Dreyfuss -- Chrisopher Reeve -- Margot Kidder -- Jon Cryer -- Jonathan Demme -- Ray Liotta -- Jeff Daniels -- Melanie Griffith -- Garson Kanin -- Michael Powell -- Sona Grant -- Mark Hamill -- Anthony Daniels -- Gary Kurtz -- Dana Carvey -- Darlene Fleugel -- Elie Wallach -- James Orr.
  - Tape Interviews nos. 1-29, 31-35, audio cassettes (Box 34)
    Olympia Dukakis (Moonstruck) -- Charles Cohen -- Wholly Moses Camel -- Ruthie Missel -- Chorus Line (Mitzi Hamilton, Susan Danielle, David Thome, Maude Dahl, Linda Hartman) -- Music Hall Closing Party -- Tom Spriggs -- Robert Frank -- Mike Schiffer -- Cleavon Little (Fletch) -- Michael Ritchie --Jonathan Sanger -- George Cashman -- Randal Cole -- Mark Johnson -- Disney Animators/Executives -- Alan Freeberg -- Colors (Sean Penn, Robert Solo, Mike Schiffer, Dennis Hopper) -- Apocalypse Now (Coppola Press Conference) -- Alan Trustman -- Albert "Cubby" Broccoli -- Ford Model Shoppe -- Peter and Joan Graves -- Ralph Bakshi -- Martin Ritt -- Cocktail (Roger Donaldson, Tom Cruise, Bob Cort, Bryan Brown, Elizabeth Shue) -- Susan Anspach -- Volker Schlondorff -- Stephen Schiff & Gerald Peary -- Ira Wohl -- Amada Peterson -- Beckman & Henshaw -- Michael Swerdlick -- Zarkas & Buro -- Steve Rash -- Shear Madness: Jake LaMotta,Vickie LaMotta,Don Cragin,Bill Grundfest,Bruce Jordan -- Disney's The Black Hole: Dr. William Kaufman -- Great American Laugh Off -- Star Trek Day -- Doug Herrick -- Jon Lipsky -- Francis O'Brien -- Delia Ephron -- Greg Mcdonald -- Mel Frank -- Art Stevens -- Peter Hazzard -- Peter Weir -- James Toback -- David Rosenbaem -- Marjle Short -- Desmond Morris -- William Shatner -- Arnold Schwarzenegger -- Allyson Reed -- Feuer & Martin -- A Chorus Line -- Bosoms and Neglect cast -- John Houseman.
  - Tape Interviews nos. 138-155, 158-160, 321, 324-326, 328-330, 332-336, audio cassettes (Box 31)
    Chevy Chase -- Steve Martin -- Alfonso Arau -- Patrice Martinez -- Jeffrey Hornaday -- Nicole Fosse -- Terry Mann -- Jan Gan Boyd -- Tony Fields -- Janet Jones -- Maurice Leduc -- Sydney Pollack -- Frank Langella -- Charles River Academy -- Andrew Stevens -- Edward R. Pressman -- Frank Perry -- Coppola -- Duvall -- Hopper -- Bottoms -- Fishburne -- Hall -- Sony Hamlin -- Burt Lancaster -- Kirk Douglas -- Karen Allen -- James Widdoes -- Chris Miller -- Craig Russell -- Hollis McLaren -- Ted Danson -- Howie Mandell -- Jennifer Edwards -- Woody Woodring -- Frederick Nolan -- Richard Dreyfuss -- Danny DeVito -- Barbara Hershey -- Barry Levinson -- Mark Johnson -- Janet Judd -- Tony Anthony -- Richard Norton -- Brooke Shields -- Martin Hewett -- Lian Brandon -- Bud Cort -- Tom Wilhite -- Wolfgang Reitherman -- Ian Richardson -- Hart Bochner -- Helen Redmond -- Alex McArthur -- Jud Nelson -- Mart Bochler -- James Caan -- Michael Mann -- Stuart Byron -- Gila Almagor -- Madison Davis Lacy, Jr. -- Barry Reardon -- David Brudnoy Show -- William Friedkin -- Tom Berenger -- Elizabeth Perkins -- Jeffrey Lurie -- Cynthia Collins -- Al Reinert -- Jan Egleson -- Elie Wiesel -- Ralph Rosenblum -- Ken Chandler -- Albert Mysles -- Zack Norman -- Josiah Spalding -- Lis Leeman -- Morris Englander.
  - Tape Interviews nos. 202-229, 232-240, audio cassettes (Box 6)
    Disney Start Tours -- David Smith -- Tony Bodner -- Jack Lindquist -- George Lucas -- Michael Eisner -- Jeffrey Katzenberg -- Orson Welles Cinema 10th anniversary -- James Bridges -- F.O.Y.B.L. (First On Your Block) Theatre -- Holodnak, Bill (Brattle Theatre) -- Precourt, Geoff -- WITS radio broadcast for "Animal House" -- Ellis, Jib -- Rodgers, David -- Horvitz, Gene -- Brandon, Liane -- Reisman, Arnie -- Bridges, James -- Geist, Kenneth L -- Klein, Maxine -- Robert Riger -- Paul C. Smith -- Joe DiMino -- Dana Hersey -- Luis & Daniel Valdez -- Charles Grodin -- Liv Ullmann -- Film Investment Symposium -- Martin Sheen -- Helen Shaver -- Mark Frost -- Beverly Cahme -- John Schlesinger -- Carla Prinza -- Robert Loggia -- David Smith -- Don Bluth (Snow White panel) -- Roddy McDowell -- Jimmy MacDonald -- Garry Marshall -- Alexandra Fose (Nothing in Common) -- Jonathan Demme -- Melvin Dummar -- Leonard Maltin -- Roderick Paul -- Myron Meisel -- John Houseman (Paper Chase) -- Ellen Feingold -- Tom Hanks -- Jackie Gleason (Nothing in Common) -- Take That Turkey and Stuff It -- Fred's Turkey House Fred Bloom -- Charlton Heston -- William Peter Blatty -- Bud Yorkin -- Martin Ritt -- Anthony Edwards -- Angelica Huston (The Dead).
    See Segaloff annotations for contents information.
  - Tape Interviews nos. 283-308, 310-313, 315-320, audio cassettes (Box 35)
    Paul Hogan -- Friedkin -- Tony Fantozzi -- Gerald Petrievich -- Brian DePalma -- Walon Green -- Ken Nordine -- Marc Weiss -- Nadia Tass -- David Pirker -- Paul Monash -- Karen Allen -- Rampage -- William Friedkin -- Ishtar (Warren Beatty, Dustin Hoffman) -- Randy Jurgensen -- Sammy Cahn -- Brinks Press Luncheon -- Bob Weiner -- Red Auerbach -- Paul Sorvino -- Saul Zaentz -- Ralph Bakshi -- Cruising -- Exorcist -- William Peter Blatty -- Leonard Maltin -- Oliver & Co. -- All Dogs Go To Heaven (Don Bluth, Olive Jar Animation) -- I.F. Stone -- Michael Ritchie -- Larry Sapadin -- Greg Moyer -- Larry Hovis -- Ray Bradbury -- John Re -- Patrick McGilligan -- David Kleiler -- Danny Peary -- Bill Smith -- Pearl Bailey -- Bill Glazer -- Off Season sound track -- Pro Football: Mayhem on a Sunday Afternoon -- Sterling "Red" Quinlan -- Thin Blue Line -- Day's End (backstage) -- Jerry Esbin -- Alan Friedberg -- George Mansour -- Colors -- Fish Called Wanda (John Cleese, Michael Palin, Michael Shamberg) -- Ed Asner -- Two on the Aisler -- David Wolper.
  - Tape Interviews nos. 338-352, 355, 357-374, audio cassettes (Box 32)
    Jim Klein -- Enrique Oliver -- Peter Filardi -- Jan Egleson -- Joe Dante -- Patrick Swayze -- Jerry Zuker -- Whoopie Goldberg -- Demi Moore -- Alice Ghostley -- Alan Friedberg -- Herring -- Reitherman -- Vheren -- D. Clem -- G. Mansour -- D. Brode -- Reisman -- P. Stupin -- O. Johnston -- J. O'Donnell -- Pat Fili -- Robin Young -- Mitch Klein -- S. Rolbein -- Margaret Joyce -- James Stewart (not Jimmy Stewart)-- Robert Altman -- Jan Egleson -- M. Viscini; O'Keefe -- Patrick Palmer -- Robert Downey -- Alan M. Dershowitz -- Walter Green -- Alan Friedberg -- Flip Johnson -- Tom Stoppard -- Boston Skyline -- Robert Wise -- Dick May -- Robert Altman -- Jonathan Demme -- Profile of Stanley Kubrick -- Stan Freberg -- Bekins Campaign -- Peter and the Network -- Woodstock: the Memory -- Kent State 10th Anniversary -- Media -- The Drizzle -- Tony Bill -- John Waters -- Lanie Zera -- Brad Jones -- Jacques D'Amboise -- Stephen Brimigham -- David Carradine -- Billy Dee Williams -- Max Von Sydow -- Marvin Hamlisch -- Jay Blackton -- Ronald Haver -- Clive Hirshorn -- Mike Weller -- Howard Teichman -- Terry Gilliam -- Dave Allen -- Anna Thomas -- Gregory Nava -- Milo O'Shea.
  - Tape Interviews nos. 36-70, audio cassettes (Box 36)
    Rob Cohen -- Ezra Sachs -- Howard Smith -- D. Rosenbaum -- S. Reynolds -- Off the Wall -- David Mendelsohn -- Larry Babb -- Ruth Avegnon -- Robert Enders -- LeVar Burton -- Jerry Jameson -- Adam Kennedy -- Peter McNichol -- Adrienne Barbeau -- Ray Harryhausen -- Margo -- Richard Schickel -- Vic Pisano -- James Bridges -- Ken Adam -- Mary Tyler Moore -- Larry Jackson -- Amy Robinson -- Ann Beattie -- Maggie Trichon -- David E. Rosenberg -- Nicolas (film) -- Sally Field -- Paul Newman -- Wilford Brimley -- Joseph Wambaugh -- Bob Miller -- Janet Buchwald -- Peter Hazzard -- Charles Kuralt -- Sandy Duncan -- John Hurt -- David Lynch -- Sylvianne Gold -- Malcolm Leo -- Martin Sheen -- David Brown -- Thomas Merton -- Vicki Frederick -- Loreen Landon -- Dean Stewart -- Jamie Lee Curtis -- Debra Hill -- Yvette Mimeux -- Maitre Jacques -- Nino Todescu -- Liane Brandon -- Deal Stolber -- MGM On Stage -- Jim Craig -- Pierce O'Neil -- Eileen Brennan -- Alan Moyle -- Robin Johnson -- Trini Alvarado -- David Selby -- People's Theatre -- Bill Frye -- Willard Huyck -- Gloria Katz -- Miles Chapin -- Michael Douglas -- Blanch Baker -- Sheri Ebner -- Paul Dergarabedian -- Mike Finnel -- Rob Bottin -- Shirley McClain -- Twiggy -- Leigh Lawson -- Shanda Ozmi -- Vito Russo -- Kaye Ballard -- Paul Katzeff -- Susan Sarandon -- tony Kahn -- Joel Robinson -- Alan Bates -- Julie Budd -- Jan Egelson -- Leigh Lawson -- Gregory Mcdonald.
  - Tape Interviews nos. 375-392, 395-400, audio cassettes (Box 28)
    Walter Bernstein -- Norman Corwin -- Jim Morris -- Gahan Wilson -- Nancy Winters -- Rosalyn Bruyere -- Leonard Maltin -- Martin Ritt -- Michael Ritchie -- Newspaper Picture -- Jan Egleson (Executive Action) -- Attack of the Sequel Monsters -- BU Radio Production Final Show -- A Filbert is a Nut -- The Comeback (Studio 640) -- Boston University Confidential -- Johh Millius Appreciation -- John Millius -- Robert S. Steele -- Close Encounters -- Funny Lady (Streisand documentary) -- Don Rickles Friar's Club Roast -- Humphrey Bogart Friar's Roast -- CBS Joy Reel -- WBUR Comedy Documentaries -- WBUR Fundraising Comedy Spots -- Oliver Stone -- Jonathan Rosenbaum -- David Shepard -- Richard Pena -- Robert A. Harris -- James C. Katz -- Larry Kardis -- Richard Kozarski -- Robert A. Harris -- Fay Kanin -- Bob Harris -- Martin Scorsese -- Sam Jaffe -- John Randolph -- Stirling Silliphant -- James Bridges Memorial.
  - Tape Interviews nos. 71-103, audio cassettes (Box 33)
    Larry Peerce -- Marilyn Hassett -- Meg Foster -- Kathleen Tynan -- Matt Siegel -- Chris Kearney -- Martin Ritt -- Richard Attenborough -- Greg Burge -- Alyson Reed -- Blane Savage -- Rory O'Connor -- Arnie Reisman -- Allan Moyle -- Steven Lack -- Who's On First -- It Came From Orson Welles -- Tim Ferris -- Barbara Aldridge -- The Roswell Report -- Rex Smith -- Chuck Barros -- John Chambers -- Guy Spencer -- Steve Schwatz -- John Waters -- Mark Johnson -- Claudia Weill -- Chris Lamonte -- Amy Stryker -- Irwin Yablans -- Robert Altman -- Ford Model Shoppe -- Jiri Menzel -- Mac Thanes -- Dudley Moore -- Jack Larson -- Mark Litwak -- Howard Koch -- Margo -- Nicholas Meyer -- The Ramones -- Peter Yates -- Vic Kemper -- Gene Callahan -- Douglas Trumbull -- Clark Smidt -- Fawlty Towers -- Brian Clark -- Glynn Turman -- Richard Tuggle -- Jenny Wright -- Joan Tewksbury -- Michelle Rappaport -- Jack Valenti -- Russ Meyer -- Joseph L. Mankiewicz -- Helene Hanff -- Albert Whitlock -- Gene Wilder -- Dom DeLuise -- Haskell Wexler -- Stephen Frears -- Gabe Kaplan -- Linda Harris -- Jim Pike -- Gene Perkins -- Dorothy DeBolt -- Peter Hazzard -- Paul A. Leu -- Martin Rosen.
  - Thomas, Frank: Interview, 1958 July 13; audio cassette (Box 25)
    Interview with Frank Thomas and Ollie Johnson, animators of the film, "Bambi."
    Tape 261
  - Valenti, Jack: Interview, 1969 February 11; audio cassette (Box 25)
    Jack Valenti and Noel Black discuss the new filmmaker's program from the MPAA at Boston Unversity as well as the new MPAA ratings system.
    Tape 252.
  - Vidgeon, Robin: Interview, 1987 August 22; audio cassette (Box 25)
    Cinematographer for the films, "Mr. North" and "Hellraiser."
    Tape no. 241.
  - Vincent, Jan-Michael: Interview, 1973 February 8; 2 audio cassettes (Box 26)
    Boston press luncheon with the actor.
    Tapes 198, 199
  - Von Sydow, Max: Interview, 1980 December 15 (Box 82)
    Discusses the film, "Flash Gordon" and singing "Helen Gor," the Swedish drinking song.
  - Williams, John: Interview, 1981 April 21; audio cassette (Box 26)
    Interview with the composer on occasion of taking over the Boston Pops.
  - Wintman, Mel: Interview, 1979 April 11; 2 audio cassettes (Box 26)
    Interview with the Vice President of General Cinema.
    Tapes 196, 197
  - Zinn, Howard: Interview, 2003 June 23 (Box 82)
  - Keiser, Elwood: Interview, 1989 September 19 (Box 82)
  - May, Dick: Interview, 1989 August 15 (Box 82)
    Interview on restoring "The Wizard of Oz.